<RulesCIS>
  <Rule id="1.1">
    <Name>Ensure pre-installation planning checklist is implemented (Manual)</Name>
    <Chapter id="1">Initial Setup</Chapter>
    <Section id="1.1">Planning and Preparation</Section>
    <SubSection id="1.1.1">Pre-Installation Planning</SubSection>

    <Profiles>
      <Profile level="1" type="Server"/>
    </Profiles>
    <BasePath>/etc/apache_planning</BasePath>
    <FileName>Pre-Installation_Checklist.txt</FileName>
    <NonCompliantComment>The pre-installation planning checklist has not been implemented, which may lead to overlooked security controls and configuration gaps.</NonCompliantComment>
    <CorrectiveComment>Review and implement all items on the pre-installation planning checklist as defined by organizational security policies.</CorrectiveComment>
    <Correction>Manual review required; update documentation and verify all checklist items are completed.</Correction>
    <Verification>Manual verification required to ensure all checklist items have been addressed.</Verification>
    <Manual>YES</Manual>
  </Rule>

  <Rule id="1.2">
    <Name>Ensure server is dedicated to Apache web services (Manual)</Name>
    <Chapter id="1">Initial Setup</Chapter>
    <Section id="1.1">Planning and Preparation</Section>
    <SubSection id="1.1.2">Server Role Limitation</SubSection>

    <Profiles>
      <Profile level="1" type="Server"/>
    </Profiles>
    <BasePath>/etc</BasePath>
    <FileName>server_usage_policy.txt</FileName>
    <NonCompliantComment>The server is configured as a multi-use system, which increases the attack surface and the risk of compromise.</NonCompliantComment>
    <CorrectiveComment>Designate the server exclusively for Apache web services by removing or disabling non-essential services.</CorrectiveComment>
    <Correction>Manual review required; update system configuration to limit the server's role to web hosting only.</Correction>
    <Verification>Manual verification required to confirm that no extraneous services are running.</Verification>
    <Manual>YES</Manual>
  </Rule>

  <Rule id="1.3">
    <Name>Ensure Apache is installed from vendor-approved binaries (Manual)</Name>
    <Chapter id="1">Initial Setup</Chapter>
    <Section id="1.1">Planning and Preparation</Section>
    <SubSection id="1.1.3">Installation Source Validation</SubSection>

    <Profiles>
      <Profile level="1" type="Server"/>
    </Profiles>
    <BasePath>/opt/apache</BasePath>
    <FileName>apache_installation</FileName>
    <NonCompliantComment>Apache is not installed using the vendor-recommended binaries, which may result in using unpatched or insecure software.</NonCompliantComment>
    <CorrectiveComment>Install Apache from the approved vendor binaries or packages to ensure that security patches and updates are provided.</CorrectiveComment>
    <Correction>Manual review required; reinstall Apache using vendor-provided packages per official documentation.</Correction>
    <Verification>Manual verification required to ensure Apache version and installation source meet vendor recommendations.</Verification>
    <Manual>YES</Manual>
  </Rule>
</RulesCIS>
